VAN HOLDER

Software Development Project Manager

📞 +1-234-456-7890 🔞 elonmusk@fakemail.com 🕜 linkedin.com/in/enhancv 👂 Santa Clara, CA

SUMMARY

Project manager with 11 years experience in software development. Developed detailed project timelines and proposed new solutions that lead to an 8% growth in annual revenue at AMD. Built solid relationships with +20 clients. Seeking a project manager position to improve profits and revenue at Acme Inc.

EDUCATION

M.S. Computer & Information Systems University of California, Los Angeles 2009 - 2010 Los Angeles, CA GPA 3.8 / 4.0

EXPERIENCE

Executive Project Manager

Advanced Micro Devices 2018 - Ongoing Santa Clara, CA AMD is an American semiconductor company based that develops computer processors and related technologies for business and consumer markets.

- · Leading and mentoring 3 teams of over 30 different scientists
- · Responsible for the budgeting, risk management and scheduling of the AMD Project Quantum development
- Created over 20 waterfall project plans for the development of new chips
- Introduced daily QA tests, increasing productivity by 30% and saving an average of \$30K per project
- Secured over 200 relationships with HP, Asus, Lenovo and Dell that ensured the use of AMD chipsets in pre-built computers

Product Manager

G-Suite 2014 - 2018 Santa Clara, CA

G-Suite is a collection of cloud computing, productivity and collaboration tools, software and products developed and marketed by Google. I worked as a project manager for the Gmail team.

- Led an international team of 15 developers and 5 designers
- Managed a \$1M/yr development budget with Oracle Project Accounting
- Improved engineering delivery times by 20% by enhancing in place Agile methodologies with tested best practices, saving Google \$150K/month
- Redesigned Gmail with the help of surveys and data processing, resulting in an overall smoother and faster experience

Assistant Product Manager

Uber 2012 - 2014 Los Angeles, CA

Uber is an American technology company. Its services include ride-hailing, food delivery, package delivery, couriers, and freight transportation.

- · Led demonstrations of product in showroom to clients and investors which helped secure \$2 million in funding in 2012
- Instituted Agile methodologies with product updates released every two weeks, speeding up the development by 20% and going out of beta 2 months earlier
- Reduced costs of printed advertising materials by 30% by negotiating prices and fees with local vendors, saving Uber \$400K
- · Managed customer complaints and settled disputes
- Implemented a new online payment solutions yielding a 30% increase in revenues

MOST PROUD OF

Developed the most popular email service Redesigned Gmail, which has 1.5B+ active users.

Securing \$2M in funding for Uber

After pitching Uber's idea to change the world of share commuting forever at StartUp Expo 2012

SKILLS

Project Management

Merlin Projects • Waterfall • Agile • Scrum •

Visio • Clarity • MS Office • Data processing •

Oracle Project Accounting •

Product roadmaps • Budgeting • Scheduling •

QA • CRM

Programming

Java • JS • HTML • CSS • VueJS • NodeJS • PHP •

Python • Databases • OOP

STRENGTHS

Leadership

I was chosen among the rest of peers for various leadership roles - Onsite Tech Lead, Project Manager and Program Manager roles for my leadership qualities.

Effective communication

Confident in communicating the idea of any product to major stakeholders.

Quick in making vital decisions

Quick in making vital decisions and remaining. I achieve this by using the Descartes Square technique.